so let's say we have something like 26
applications in a benchmark Suite how do
we summarize the overall performance of
a machine on the entire Suite so we want
a single number that represents the
performance of the machine usually we
want to use something like the average
execution time so let's say we have a
computer X and a computer Y A Benchmark
application a b and c and let's say that
computer X takes 9 seconds here 10
seconds here and 5 Seconds here whereas
the computer y takes 18 seconds here 7
Seconds here and 11 seconds here the
speed up of machine X over machine y on
each of these applications is two for
application a because X is doing it in
half the time as y 0.7 on application B
Because X is actually slower than y
there and here it's 2.2 because X is
more than twice as fast as y now let's
compute the average
execution time here we have 9 + 10 + 5
over 3 gives us 8 seconds so on average
computer X finishes one of these three
applications in 8 seconds on average
computer y finishes one of these three
in 18 + 7 + 11 over 3 12 seconds if we
now compute the speed up of X over y on
average it will be 1.5 when comp
computed this way but if we average the
speed UPS here we get 1.63 so if we want
to use average execution times we cannot
simply average the speed UPS on
individual applications to get the
average speed up pretty much the speed
up using average execution times is not
the same as the average of speed UPS on
these individual applications if we want
to be able to average speed UPS then we
need to use geometric means for both of
our application execution times and for
our speed UPS in that case we get a
geometric mean of 7.66 here
11.15 here and 1.4 56 here so we have
used the geometric mean for the
execution times for each of the computer
if we use the geometric mean for these
speedups we will get the same value here
the geometric mean is computed by
multiplying out for example 9 * 10 * 5
and then taking the nth root in this
case third root of the value to get the
geometric mean and because things are
being multiplied out and then the nend
through take and you can see how if we
divide these things we will get that the
speed up computed geometric means of
execution times will be the same as the
mean of the speed UPS because we have 3
root of 18 * 7 * 11 these two divided is
the same as thir root of 9 18 * 10/ 7 *
5 11 so as you can see this is the
geometric mean of execution times then
we can compute the speed up using them
and that's the same as the geometric
mean of individual speedups however this
only works for geometric means we do
prefer average execution time when we
are Computing the average times however
just you must be careful not to compute
individual speedups and then a a them
instead you should be Computing the
average execution times and then
Computing the speed up using those
averages you should also remember that
simple average should not be used on
ratios of times so basically a speed up
here is a ratio of two times we should
not be using a simple arithmetic mean on
these values because they are ratios
geometric means on the other hand can be
used on ratios but for for this to work
we also have to use geometric mean on
times too